# Suseendhar Lal Lakshmiramiya Sridhar

Email: <a href="mailto:lssuseendharlal@gmail.com">lssuseendharlal@gmail.com</a> Phone: +91 8012543335/7904217073

Portfolio: suseendhar.netlify.app

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/suseendhar-lal

GitHub: github.com/suseendharlal96 Twitter: twitter.com/SuseendharL

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

Having 2 and half years of experience in IT Infrastructure as a Full stack developer on developing and hosting Web Applications, I take responsibility of developing responsive sites using HTML, CSS and JS along with latest frameworks and libraries like Reactjs, Redux, Angular7, Nodejs, Mongodb. As a good team player, I've developed websites using Reactjs(also Angular & Vuejs), Redux, Nodejs, Mongodb along with GraphQL from the scratch which includes all the authentication and core stuffs for a website.

#### PROGRAMMING SKILLS

• Languages: HTML, JavaScript and Typescript

• Software Development Methodologies: Agile (Scrum)

• **AWS:** S3, Lambda.

• JS Frameworks: ReactJS with Redux, VueJS with Vuex, Angular, JQuery, NextJS, GatsbyJS.

• CSS Frameworks: Bootstrap, Material-ui for React, Semantic-ui React.

• **APIs:** RESTful(NodeJS), GraphQL(Apollo), Google's Firebase.

• **DB**: MongoDB

• Version Control: Git, Git Hub

• IDEs: Visual Studio Code

• Hosting platforms: Netlify, Heroku

• Content Management System: Contentful

• **Testing Tools:** *Postman* 

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Junior Software Engineer**

Feb 2019 – Present

Object Frontier Software, Chennai, India

- Used HTML,SCSS, JavaScript to build web applications and web services.
- Developed mobile friendly websites using React along with Redux for store management.
- Used Material-ui, Bootstrap for creating responsive sites.
- Created RESTful services using NodeJs and stored data on Mongodb using mongoose as ORM.
- Used React hook form for client-side validations and React router for navigations.
- Implemented JWT tokens and encryption for authentication on server side
- Participated in Knowledge building activities and incorporated it in everyday tasks.

### **Software Engineer Trainee**

Sep 2018 - Feb 2019

Object Frontier Software, Chennai, India

- Trained in JavaScript, Object-oriented programming and frameworks like Angular and React.
- Built a full stack application using React as front-end, Node for RESTful API's and MongoDB using Mongoose ORM.

#### PERSONAL WORKS

- Constantly keep up-to-date with latest technologies and publish code on GitHub.
- My personal works: <u>suseendhar.netlify.app/projects</u>

## **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Science and Engineering)**

Aug 2014 – Apr 2018

Rajalakshmi Engineering College, Chennai, India

## ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS

- Bagged First prize in Camlin District Arts competition.
- Received gold medal for Velammal National level science talent exam.
- Received proficiency for emerging as Academic topper.